Finding Aid for J. Edwin Ellis scrapbooks, 1909-1947
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
J. Edwin Ellis scrapbooks 1909-1947
Ellis, J. Edwin.
1 linear foot and 10 oversize volumes
851178 Aa 2; AC
Mayor of Owosso, Michigan, and life-long supporter and chronicler of the career of Thomas E. Dewey. Scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings, correspondence and campaign miscellanea relating primarily to Dewey's legal career in New York State and his political activities, particularly his campaign for the Presidency in 1944.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of this collection is unclear.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
J. Edwin Ellis was mayor of Owosso, Michigan. In addition, he was a life-long supporter of Thomas E. Dewey who was also from Owosso.
The collection consists of scrapbooks relating to the career of Thomas E. Dewey. The scrapbooks begin in 1909, but only go up to 1947, and thus do not cover Dewey's 1948 Presidential campaign or his later career.
Subjects:
Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1865-1950.; Owosso (Mich.); Presidents--United States--Election--1944.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Publications, clippings, etc.
  - Political papers, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Thomas E. Dewey: Racket Buster (New York: One-Slot Publishing Co., n.d. ), 2 copies (Box 1)
  - "Attorney for the People. The Life Story of Thomas E. Dewey."Liberty Magazine, October 21, 1939 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1909-1947
  - 1909-1919 and 1927-1935 (Box 1)
    (Vol. 1)
  - 1937-July 1939 (Volume 2)
    (Vol. 2)
  - July 1939-December 1939 (Volume 3)
    (Vol. 3)
  - January 1940-April 1940 (Volume 4)
    (Vol. 4)
  - February 1940-August 1942 (Volume 5)
    (Vol. 5)
  - August 1942-June 1944 (Volume 6)
    (Vol. 6)
  - June 1944-July 1944 (Volume 7)
    (Vol. 7)
  - July 1944-September 1944 (Volume 8)
    (Vol. 8)
  - July 1944-October 1944 (Volume 9)
    (Vol. 9)
  - October 1944-December 1946 (Volume 10)
    (Vol. 10)
  - January 1947-November 1947 (Volume 11)
    (Vol. 11)